hey guys this looks like a fun one we're
gonna find the area of the blue region
contained by these lines and the y-axis
if you want to try this on your own
pause it right now because I'm going to
solve it in three two one the equations
of these lines are given to us in
standard form I want to rewrite them as
y equals MX plus b which is known as
slope intercept form because m is the
slope of the line and B is the
y-intercept of the line let's take the
first equation X Plus y equals five and
in order to rewrite it in slope
intercept form we need to get y by
itself so we're going to subtract X from
both sides these X's are going to cancel
so the left hand side is just going to
be Y and on the right hand side we have
Negative X plus five and now we have
slope intercept form so I'm going to
rewrite X Plus y equals 5 as y equals
negative X plus five and let's do the
same thing for this lower one we'll copy
it down we're going to subtract X from
both sides left hand side is 2y right
hand side is negative X plus six and
then we're going to divide both sides by
2. left hand side is just Y and we're
going to divide each of these by two so
negative x divided by 2 is negative one
half X and 6 divided by 2 is 3. and now
we can change this lower equation up
here and do slope intercept form so now
let's use our equations to find the
y-intercepts this one up here it says
the Y intercept is five so this point is
going to be 0 5. and for this equation
the Y intercept is three so this vertex
is located at 0 3. so now that we have
these two vertices let's find this third
one and the best way to do that is set
these two equations equal to each other
and I will tell us the X and the Y point
where they're both equal to each other
so our goal is to solve for x in this
first thing I don't like fractions I'm
going to multiply both sides by two the
two will distribute so 2 times negative
X is negative 2X and 2 times 5 is equal
to 10 and this will be equal to this 2
distributed to both of these two times
negative one-half is negative one and
then times x is negative X and then 2
times 3 is equal to 6. now we want to
move both X's to the same side if I add
2x to both sides negative 2X and 2x
cancel each other out negative X plus 2X
is equal to one X and we bring down the
six now we want to get this x by itself
so we subtract 6 from both sides 10
minus 6 is equal to 4 and these cancel
leaving us with just X now we know that
the X that this intersection point is
equal to four so we can change that to a
four and then to find out what the
corresponding Y is we can plug this 4 in
4X for either one of these equations I
think it'll be easier to do this top
equation so we're going to substitute 4
into the X and negative 4 plus 5 is
equal to 1. so the Y value of this point
is one and we don't need this anymore in
fact now that we have the location of
our vertices we don't need our equations
anymore either so if this has a height
of 3 and this has a height of 5 that
means the distance is 2 in between them
and let's find this distance as well
since this x value is 4 we're going from
0 to 4 which means this distance right
here is four and now we really don't
even need these points anymore and let's
rotate this and now we want to find the
area of this triangle the area of a
triangle is one half base times height
the base of this triangle is equal to
two and the height of this triangle is
equal to four the one-half times two
just cancel each other out so we have an
area of four units squared so the area
of this blue region is equal to four
units squared now we can put a box
around that how exciting